Guide to the A Gathering of the Tribes Records MSS.198
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series IV. Grant Files, 1994-2010; 3 Linear Feet in 4 manuscript boxes and 1 unknown profile container
  - New York State Council on the Arts - Digital Tech Initiatives, Literary Publishing, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 60)
  - New York State Council on the Arts Final Report Fiscal Year 01, 2000-2001 (Box 19, Folder 61)
  - New York State Council on the Arts - Request and Grant Return, 2000-2001 (Box 19, Folder 62)
  - New York State Council on the Arts Sup - Reading Series, Fiscal Year 02, 2000-2002 (Box 19, Folder 63)
  - New York State Council on the Arts, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 64)
  - New York State Council on the Arts - Grant, Fiscal Year '02, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 65)
  - New York State Council on the Arts - Contract, Final Report, Fiscal Year '02, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 66)
  - New York State Council on the Arts, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 67)
  - New York State Council on the Arts '01-'02 Blank Form, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 68)
  - New York State Council on the Arts - Final Report Literature, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 69)
  - New York State Council on the Arts, 2003-2010 (Box 35, Folder 17-19)
  - Non-Profit Finance Fund, 2000-2002 (Box 19, Folder 70)
  - Program Budgets, 2005 (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Puffin Foundation, 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 71)
  - Puffin Foundation Fiscal Year '01, 1999-2000 (Box 19, Folder 72)
  - Puffin Foundation, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 73)
  - Puffin Foundation, Fiscal Year '00 Request, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 74)
  - Puffin Foundation (12/01) Grant Application, Decmber 2001 (Box 19, Folder 75)
  - Puffin Foundation, 2005 (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - Richard and Hinda Rosenthal Foundation, 2005 (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - Robert Sterling Clark, 2005-2006 (Box 35, Folder 23)
  - The Russell Berrie Foundation, 2005 (Box 35, Folder 24)
  - The Scherman Foundation, 2005-2006 (Box 35, Folder 25)
  - Sony Pictures -- Corporate Affairs, 2003 (Box 35, Folder 26)
  - Stephen A. and Diana L. Goldberg Foundation, 2005 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Susana Maio Grant Research, 2005 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Van Pelt Foundation, 2005 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Victor Herbert Foundation, 2005 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Wachovia Foundation, 2005 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Washington Mutual, 2005 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Workshop Contract, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 76)
  - WTC Business Recovery Grant Program, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 77)
  - Yaron Foundation, 2005 (Box 36, Folder 7)
- Series V. Financial Records, 1998-2005; 3 Linear Feet in 3 containers without profiles.
  This series contains financial files which include bills, tax returns, budgets, account statements, ledgers, and cancelled checks for A Gathering of the Tribes.
  - Budgets, 2000 (Actual) - 2003 (Projected) (Box 19, Folder 78)
  - Check Ledgers, 2001-2002 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Check Ledgers, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Check Ledgers, 2002-2003 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Check Ledgers, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Check Ledgers, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Check Ledgers, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Checking Account Statements, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 79)
  - Checking Account Statements (1 of 2), 2000-2005 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Checking Account Statements (2 of 2), 2000-2005 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Checking Account Statements, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Checking Account Statements, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Checking Account Statements, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Checking Account Statements, 2002-2003 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Checking Account Statements, 2002-2003 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Checks, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Checks, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Checks, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Checks, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Checks, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Checks, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Checks, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Checks, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Online Magazine Budget, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Receipts, 2000-2002 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Tax / Account Stuff, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Tax / Account Stuff (1 of 3), 1999 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Tax / Account Stuff (2 of 3), 1999 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Tax / Account Stuff (3 of 3), 1999 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Tax / Account Stuff, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Tax / Account Stuff, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Tax Returns, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Tax Returns, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Tax Returns, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Tax Returns, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Tribes Bills, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Tribes Bills, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Tribes Bills, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 30)
- Series VI. Publications, 1993-2019; 2 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and 2 containers without profiles.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by author's last name.
  This series contains books and serial publications published by Fly By Night Press, which was administered by A Gathering of the Tribes. Publications by other small press companies are also in this series.
  - Afflick, Lester. I Dream About You Baby. Fly By Night Press, 2008 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Axel, Brett. First on the Fire. New York: Fly By Night, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Barrio, Itziar. Pink Car Crash. Fly By Night Press, 2008 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Benson, Tish. Wild Like That: Good Stuff Smellin Strong. New York: Fly By Night, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    Scope and Content
    Introduction by Sapphire.
  - Berrios, Luciann. Thunder and Sunshine in One Body. Fly By Night Press, 2017 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Berrios, Luciann. Women of Eve's Garden. Fly By Night Press, 2018 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - The Best American Bookstore of 1998. Fly By Night Press, 2009 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Boadiba. Under Burning White Sky. Berkeley, CA: Ishmael Reed Publishing Company, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Carter, Michael. Broken Noses and Metempsychoses. New York: Fly By Night, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Chaluisan, Luis. Spic Chic. Fly By Night Press, 2009 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Don, Gabriel. Living Without Sin. Fly By Night Press, 2019 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Farris, John. It's Not About Time. Fly By Night Press, 1993 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Feast, Jim. Time Extends Life to Those Who Survive. Fly By Night Press, 2016 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Freedman, Katherine Rose. Straight to the Point. Westport, CT: RozyPozy Press, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Goodreaux, Melanie Maria. Black Jelly. Fly By Night Press, 2019 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Kim, Anyssa. Ovarian Twists: New and Selected Poems. New York: Fly By Night, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Kolm, Ron. Divine Comedy. Fly By Night Press, 2013 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Kosiewicz, Patrick. The Geoglyph. Fly By Night Press, 2009 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Laskin, Pamela. Daring Daughters / Defiant Dreams. Fly By Night Press, 2012 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Maldonado, Sheila. One-Bedroom Solo. Fly By Night Press, 2011 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Mozon, Nadine. Kiss it Up to God. New York: Fly By Night, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Murphy, Jennifer. Remain. New York: Fly By Night, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Otomo, Yuko. Garden. Fly By Night Press, 2009 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Ouzoonian, Amy, ed. In the Arms of Words: Poems for Disaster Relief. Santa Fe: Sherman Asher, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Ouzoonian, Amy, ed. Skyscrapers, Taxis and Tampons. New York: Fly By Night, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Ouzoonian, Amy. Found in Phoenix. Fly By Night Press, 2014 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Packer, Eve. Skulls Head Samba. New York: Fly By Night, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Parker, Eve. New Nails. Fly By Night Press, 2011 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Pflanzer, Howard. Dead Birds or Avian Blues. Fly By Night Press, 2011 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Purcell, Barbara. Black Ice. New York: Fly By Night, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Rux, Carl Hancock. Pagan Operetta. New York: Fly By Night, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Semerdjian, Alan. An Improvised Device. Lock n' Load Press, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Sit, Joanna. Track Works. Fly By Night Press, 2017 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Slote, J.P. The Body of Loretta. Fly By Night Press, 2019 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Taylor, Cheryl Boyce. Raw Air. New York: Fly By Night, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Watson, Carl. Astral Botanica. Fly By Night Press, 2014 (Box 38, Folder 8)
- Series VII. Steve Cannon Papers, 1976-2019; 3 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize flat box, and 1 file in a shared tall LP box.; 778 kilobytes In 11 computer files.
  This series is arranged beginning with writings grouped and listed in chronological order, followed by the remaining files in chronological order.
  This series focuses on material specifically related to A Gathering of the Tribes founder Steve Cannon. Manuscripts date from 1969 to 2007 and include play scripts, short stories, novels, and essays written by Cannon. He was visually impaired for the later part of his life and would often co-write or use a transcriber, which is notated in the credit line of his later works. Files concerning the rights and use of his work Groove, Bang and Jive Around include forms, correspondence, as well as a copy of a music album that used his title. Interview transcripts and press clippings on Cannon are also in this series. Ephemera from events to honor and celebration Cannon's life are in this series including posters, a handkerchief, and postcards. Documentation related to Cannon's struggle to maintain his home within the A Gathering of the Tribes building after he had sold it to a buyer can also be found in this series dating from 2012-2014.
  - Writings -- Inner Sanctums Are Kind of Blue, 1976 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Writings -- Mama Louise..., 1978 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Writings -- Plays by Cannon, 1991, undated (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Writings -- The Setup, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Writings -- Nothing to Lose, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Writings -- The Top of the World, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Writings -- Reminiscin' in C..., 1994 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Writings -- D.A.T., with Judi Rymer, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Writings -- Going Blind, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Writings -- Groove, Bang and Jive Around (1969) -- Rights, Agreements, Correspondence, 1996-1998, 2016 (Box 37, Folder 7-8)
  - Writings -- Groove, Bang and Jive Around (1969) -- Limited Edition Album by illy B Eats, Using Cannon's Title, 2006 (Box Shared Fales 046, Folder 9)
  - Writings -- Oops, 1997 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Writings -- Spell, 1998 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Writings -- Essays, 2003-2004 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Writings -- Johnson, with Judi Rymer, 2007 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Writings -- Go Figure, undated (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Writings -- Now What, What Now with Jessie Onuf, undated (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Writings -- Chump Change, undated (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Publication -- The Fuse, Cannon Mention, 1993 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Articles, 1984-2016 (Box 36, Folder 10, Box 43, Folder 4, Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Housing Issue Documentation, 2014 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Eviction Notice, 2012; cuid40334 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_198_ER_5)
  - Brother's Memorial Service Program, 2014 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Celebrations for Steve Cannon -- Flier, Promotional Material, 2014, 2019 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Handkerchief with Cannon's Birth and Death Dates, 2019 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Transcription from Podcast Interview with Cannon, undated (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Sketched Portrait of Cannon by Unknown Artist, undated (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Poster -- Tribute to Steve Cannon "Love You Madly", undated (Box 45, Folder 6)